A Guide to the Film collection FA466
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Nelson A. Rockefeller, Political Career, 14
  - 1958
    - Senator Javits Speech, 1958 October 20; Sound, Black & white, 15 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel III 14.1 Fd 3, Reel AV 1559)
      Senator Javits speech on behalf of NAR gubernatorial campaign
    - Five Candidates: Rockefeller on the Issues, 1958 (Reel III 14.1 Fb 50, Reel AV 1659)
    - Keating Interview, 1958 (Reel III 14.1 Fb 51, Reel AV 1655)
  - 1959
    - NAR on Meet the Press, 1959 July 19.; Sound, Black & white, 25 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1082, Reel III 14.1 Ff 11)
      Interviews with Governor Rockefeller.
    - Paul Coates Show Interview with Governor Rockefeller, 1959 December 1; Sound, Black & white, 25 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel III 14.1 Ff 12, Reel AV 1083)
  - 1960
    - Governor Rockefeller Reports: Budget, 1960; Sound, Black & white, 15 minutes. Only available on 16mm film. (Reel III 14.1 Fd 49, Reel AV 1678)
      A discussion with Senator Austin Erwin, finance commissioner, from a series of broadcast reports filmed by CBS.
    - NAR on Face the Nation, 1960 July 3; Sound, Black & white, 25 minutes. Only available on 16mm film. (Reel AV 1079, Reel III Ff 13)
    - Making of the President, Sound, Black & white, 1.5 hours. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1148, Reel III 14.1 Fg 36)
      Based on the book by Theodore H. White, this documentary film follows the campaigns of Nixon and JFK during the 1960 presidential election, with news footage of Nelson Rockefeller, Hubert Humphreys, and others. Produced by David Wolper for ABC News.
    - 1960 National Campaign, Sound, Black & white, 1-4 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1184, Reel III 14.1 Fa 81, Reel AV 1232, Reel III 14.1 Fa 30)
      Titles include "LEADERSHIP", "ECONOMIC GROWTH", "EQUAL OPPORTUNITY", "FOREIGN POLICY", "CIVIL RIGHTS" and"DISARMAMENT"
    - NAR Endorses Nixon in His Campaign for Presidency, 1960; Sound, Black & white, 9 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1542, Reel III 14.1 Fd 15)
      Governor Rockefeller and President Eisenhower endorse Nixon as the Republican presidential candidate.
    - National Campaign: Eisenhower for Nixon, 1960; Sound, Black & white, 4 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1234, Reel III 14.1 Fa 83)
      Footage from Channel E-24 of the New York Republican State Committee, during the 1960 presidential election.
    - National Campaign: GOP National Convention 1960, Sound, Black & white, 11 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel III 14.1 Fd 21, Reel AV 1146)
      Footage of Barry M. Goldwater's speech at the 1960 GOP Convention, 'withdrawing his candidacy in support of Richard Nixon. Goldwater speaks about the history and purpose of the Republican party, and asks for unity within the party,
    - National Campaign: NAR on the Kennedy Record, 1960; Sound, Black & white, 4 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel III 14.1 Fa 82, Reel AV 1233)
      Footage from Channel E-24 from the 1960 presidential election
  - 1961
    - Governor Rockefeller Reports: Proposals to the Legislature, 1961 January 1; Sound, Black & white, 15 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel III 14.1 Fd 50, Reel AV 1683)
      One episode from a series of broadcast reports, filmed by CBS on 1961 January 1.
    - Dr. Martin Luther King: The American Dream, 1961 July 13; Sound, no picture, 60 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1102, Reel AV 1103, Reel III 14.1 Fe 48)
      Audio of Nelson Rockefeller speech about Martin Luther King Jr. at Syracuse University
  - 1962
    - Pre-Convention Campaign Commercials., 1962; Sound/Silent, Black & white, varying lengths, usually about 1 minute. Only available on original 16mm film.
      Contains about 40 commercials from NAR's 1962 Gubernatorial campaign. Some duplicates or revised versions included.
      - Aid to Labor, 1962; Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1176)
      - Aid to New York City, 1962; Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1225, Reel AV 1224)
      - Atomic Research, 1962; Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1177)
      - Civil Rights and the Aged, 1962; Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1183)
      - College, 1962; Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1162)
      - College Education, 1962; Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1167, Reel AV 1158, Reel AV 1169)
      - Conservation and Recreation, 1962; Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1178)
      - Education, 1962; Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1174)
      - Fiscal Integrity, 1962; Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1175)
      - Higher Education, 1962; Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1180)
      - Highway Construction, 1962; Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1179)
      - Housing, 1962; Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1229, Reel AV 1168)
      - Housing and Urban Renewal, 1962; Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1181)
      - Human Rights, 1962; Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1160)
      - Jobs, 1962; Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1165, Reel AV 1154)
      - Jobs and Economic Growth, 1962; Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1230)
      - Law and Narcotics, 1962; Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1182)
      - Money, 1962; Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1166)
      - NAR: Albany, 1962; Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1171)
      - NAR: Buffalo, 1962; Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1172)
      - NAR: New York City, 1962; Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1173)
      - Narcotics, 1962; Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1231)
      - New Yorker, 1962; Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1164)
      - Record, 1962; Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1226)
      - Record, New York City, 1962; Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1159, Reel AV 1222, Reel AV 1227)
      - Record, Upstate, 1962; Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1228, Reel AV 1223)
      - School Aid, 1962; Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1170, Reel AV 1161, Reel AV 1157)
      - Senior Citizens, 1962; Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1156)
      - Women, 1962; Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1163)
    - 1962 Address to the New York State Legislature, 1962 January 1; Sound, Black & white, 60 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel AV 1716, Reel AV 1717, Reel III 14.1 Fg 5, Reel III 14.1 Fg 4)
      CBS coverage of state address by Governor Rockefeller.
    - NAR on At The Source, 1962 January; Sound, Black & white, 25 minutes. Only available on 16mm film. (Reel AV 1084, Reel III 14.1 Ff 14)
    - NAR on Newsmakers, 1962 October 21; Sound, Black & white, 28 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1094, Reel III 14.1 Ff 15)
    - Pure Water Bonds Proposition 1 Commercials, 1963; Sound, Black & white, 1 minute each. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1204, Reel AV 1205, Reel AV 1207, Reel AV 1206)
      Several public service announcements that ran on TV in 1963 in support of Pure Bond issues.
    - Gov Rockefeller Swearing-In Official Highlights, 1962 December 31; Silent, Black & white, 2 minutes, Only available on DVD. (Reel AV 1545, Reel III 14.1 Fa 60)
      Shot at Albany Executive Mansion.
  - 1963
    - Governor Rockefeller Inauguration, 1963 January 1; Sound and silent. Black & white, 25 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel AV 1666, Reel III 14.1 Fd 26)
    - NAR on Newsmakers, 1963 February 23; Sound, Black & white, 28 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1095, Reel III 14.1 Ff 16)
    - Interview on Latin American Common Market Affairs, 1963 March 13; Sound, Black & white, 16 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1086, Reel III 14.1 Fe 16)
      Governor Rockefeller interviewed for KRNT-TV in Des Moines, Iowa
    - Episode of Meet the Press, 1963 September 15; Sound, Black & white, 30 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel III 14.1 Ff 17, Reel AV 1267)
      Episode begins with NBC coverage of the bombing of an African-American church in Birmingham, Alabama. Followed by episode of Meet the Press hosted by Ned Brooks. Includes original commercials. Filmed during presidential campaign.
    - Visit to Colby Junior College, 1963 October 19; Silent, Black & white, 1 minute. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel III 14.1 Fa 106, Reel AV 1257)
      Governor Rockefeller with wife, Happy, visiting Colby Junior College
    - Pure Waters Conference, 1963 November 12; Sound, Black & white, 3 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel III 14.1 Fa 70, Reel AV 1221)
      WRGB footage from the Pure Waters Conference held in the Capitol Building, Albany, after passage of the Pure Waters Bond Issue Prop #1.
    - NAR on Face the Nation, 1963 November 17; Sound, Black & white, 25 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel III 14.1 Ff 22, Reel AV 1097)
      episode filmed during presidential campaign
    - Nelson Rockefeller: The Man and His Record, 1963; Sound, Black & white, 15 minutes. Only available on 16mm film. (Reel III 14.5 11)
      Campaign film produced during the 1963 gubernatorial race. Includes brief 'life history of NAR and footage of him at Princeton, Rockefeller Center, and in Latin America. Showcases NAR's experiences, shows him with political associates, amid NY industries and farms, visiting SUNY schools and as commissioner of the Human Rights Office.
  - 1964
    - NAR and Staff, Silent, Black & white, 1 minute. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1066)
      Brief clip of Nelson Rockefeller with his staff at West 55th Street office; shot by Wolper Productions for campaign film "Making of the President 1964".
    - 1964 California: San Diego, Kiwanis Club, Silent, Black & white, 50 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1587, Reel III 14.1 Fe 5)
    - Rockefeller's Way, 1964; Sound, Black & white, 5 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1251, Reel III 14.1 Fa 100)
      Campaign spot from 1964 California primary
    - The Extremists, 1964; Sound, Black & white, 30 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1155, Reel III 14.1 Fe 70)
      A never-aired 1964 campaign film produced by Nelson Rockefeller And Dave Garroway about the Minutemen, the John Birch Society, and other extremist groups.
    - Gov. Rockefeller Interrupted by Baby, 1964 February 28; Sound, Black & white, 20 seconds. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 75, Reel III 14 F 26)
      Nelson Rockefeller speech about opposing unilateral negations with Russia interrupted a baby laughing, during New Hampshire primary.
    - NAR on Face the Nation, 1964 March 8; Sound, Black & white, 20 minutes. Only availble on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1081, Reel III 14.1 Fg 38)
      Filmed during presidential campaign.
    - Gov. Rockefeller in New Orleans, 1964 April; Sound, Black & white, 15 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1087, Reel III 14.1 Fd 20)
      Speech on Inter-American affairs.
    - 1964 Campaign Interview, 1964 June 1; Sound, Black & white, 60 minutes. Available on DVD. (Box 2, Dvd AV 1387, Reel III 14.1 Fg 16, Reel AV 1941)
      Nelson Rockefeller interview on The Irv Kupcinet Show during presidential campaign.
    - NAR Address to the Republican National Convention, Sound, Black & white, 8 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel AV 1099, Box 2, Dvd AV 1099, Reel III 14.1 Fe 2)
    - Gov. Rockefeller Speech at Stanford University, 1964; Sound, Black & white, 11 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel AV 1697, Reel III 14.1 Fd 23)
      Speech about the UN during California primary
    - Gov. Rockefeller Speech at UCLA, 1964; Sound, Black & white, 20 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1077, Reel III 14.1 Fd 24)
      Nelson Rockefeller speech outdoors at UCLA, then inside for question/answer session with students during California primary.
    - Gov. Rockefeller in Palm Springs and San Diego, 1964; Silent, Black & white, 50 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1268, Reel III 14.1 Fg 3)
      Campaigning during California primary.
    - 1964 Address to the New York State Legislature, Sound, Black & white, 22 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel III 14.1 Fd 28, Reel AV 1076)
      Governor Rockefeller annual address to the state legislature, filmed in Albany, NY.
    - 1964 Oregon Primary, Silent, Color and Black & white, 7 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel III 14.1 Fa 84, Reel AV 1235)
      footage of Nelson Rockefeller campaigning throughout Oregon during presidential campaign, with some nonpolitical footage of wildlife, landscapes, and aerial views of the state.
  - 1965
    - NAR on Face the Nation, 1965 July 25; Sound, Black & white, 25 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel III 14.1 Ff 18, Reel AV 1089)
    - Orange, Chenango and St. Lawrence County Fairs, 1965 August; Silent, Black & white, 28 minutes. Available on DVD. (Box 1, Dvd AV 3.9, Reel AV 1597, Reel III 14.1 Fe 17)
      Nelson Rockefeller with wife at NY county fairs.
    - Camp Drum, Monroe, and Steuben County Fairs, 1965 August; Silent, Black & white, 50 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel AV 1596, Reel III 14.1 Fe 18, Box 1, Dvd AV 3.9)
      Nelson Rockefeller with wife at public events around the state.
    - Gov Rockefeller and Wife at Fort Schuyler, Bronx, NY, 1965 August 24; Silent, Black & white, 11 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel AV 1556, Reel III 14.1 Fb 12, Box 1, Dvd AV 3.10)
      Footage of military ship "Empire State IV" arriving at Fort Schuyler in the Bronx; crowds of families waiting to greet sailors. Shot by Hal Posner.
    - Adirondack: Horseback Ride Through Forest Preserve, 1965 October 10; Silent, Black & white, 20 seconds. Available on DVD. (Reel AV 1214, Reel III 14.1 Fa 62, Box 1, Dvd AV 3.38)
      edited footage from UPI Commercial News Service provided to New York State television stations.
    - Gov. Rockefeller at Dr. King's Ebenezer Church in Atlanta GA, 1965 October 17; Silent, Black & white, 20 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel III 14.1 Fd 33, Reel AV 1696, Box 1, Dvd AV 3.10)
      Governor Rockefeller visits Ebenezer Church in Atlanta with Reverend Martin Luther King Sr. and Jr.
    - UN Plaza Dedication, 1965 October 25; Silent, Black & white, 1 minute. Available on DVD. (Reel AV 1546, Reel III 14.1 Fa 64, Box 1, Dvd AV 3.10)
      Ceremony and presentation of memorial stairway and flagpole in honor of Dog Hammarskjold, secretary-president of the United Nations, at UN Plaza in New York City.
    - Man in Office, 1965 October 31; Sound, Black & white, 30 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel III 14.1 Ff 24, Reel AV 1752)
      Governor Rockefeller interviewed by Joe Michaels on NBC.
    - NAR on Issues and Answers, 1965 November 7; Sound, Black & white, 28 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel III 14.1 Ff 20, Reel AV 1639)
    - Gov. Rockefeller Receives Award from Nation Council of Christians and Jews, 1965 November 15; Sound, Black & white, 20 seconds. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel III 14.1 Fa 65, Reel AV 1216)
      CBS footage of award ceremony at Hilton Hotel in NYC
  - 1966
    - 1966 Campaign Commercials, Sound, Black & white, 23 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel III 14.1 Fd 54, Reel AV 1147)
      Sample reel of campaign commercials from 1966 gubernatorial race.
    - The Time is Now, 1966; Sound, Black & white, 20 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1109)
      Political film produced by the Republican National Finance Committee before the 1966 election. Discusses domestic and international issues that have been caused by the Democratic majority in the U.S., with sound bites from Eisenhower, Ford, Nixon, Gov. Rockefeller, and others.
    - Friend of the Rockefeller Team: Campaign Commercials 1, 1966; Sound, Black & white, 22 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1110)
      Compilation of 31 political ads from 1966 campaign, ranging from 10 to 60 seconds each. Topics include: Pure Water Program, state scholarships, the Bureau of Consumer Protection, Medicaid, the narcotics reform laws, education, minimum wage, air pollution, and a message from Jacob Javits.
    - Friend of the Rockefeller Team: Campaign Commercials 2, 1966; Sound, Color, 5 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1114)
      Compilation of 4 campaign commercials produced for the 1966 campaign (?): "4 R's" (education),"Pay Envelope" (jobs), "Consumer Fraud" (consumer protection), "Detective" (criminal intelligence system).
    - 1966 Address to the New York State Legislature, 1966 January 5; Sound, Black & white, 60 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel III 14.1 Fg 6, Reel AV 1739)
      footage of Governor Rockefeller address, shot by the NYS Department of Commerce
    - The State Vs. the Addict, 1966 March 6; Sound, Black & white, 30 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel III 14.1 Ff 37, Reel AV 1075)
      Panel discussion with Nelson Rockefeller, Donald Louria, Wyatt Tee Walker, interviewed by Bill Beutel and Murphy Martin.
    - Opening of Republican State Committee Campaign Headquarters, 1966 June 6; Sound, Black & white, 30 seconds. Available on DVD. (Reel AV 1220, Box 2, Dvd AV 1220, Reel III 14.1 Fa 69)
      from 1966 campaign, footage of Governor Rockefeller, Governor Malcolm Wilson, Attn. General Louis Lefkowitz at the Hilton Hotel in NYC.
    - Formal Announcement of Candidacy, 1966 April 6; Sound, Black & white, 20 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel III 14.1 Fe 14, Reel AV 1583, Reel III 14.1 Fe 15, Box 1, Dvd AV 3.10, Reel AV 1591)
      Nelson Rockefeller announces his intention to run for governor
    - Labor and the Public Employee, 1966 May 15; Sound, Black & white, 30 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1753, Reel III 14.1 Ff 38)
      Discussion between Nelson Rockefeller, George Taylor, and Mort Dean, shown live on CBS.
    - Governor Rockefeller's Acceptance Speech, 1966 September; Sound, Black & white, 30 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel AV 1599, Reel III 14.1 Fe 19)
      NAR acceptance speech at the GOP State Convention, with an introduction from Senator Jacob Javits, broadcast live.
    - Election Night Victory, 1966 November 8; Silent, Black & white, 10 minutes. Available on DVD. (Box 1, Dvd AV 3.11, Reel AV 3.11, Reel III 14.1 Fe 61)
      Highlights of NAR victory speech at Hilton Hotel in New York, Footage of Lieutenant Governor Malcolm Wilson, Attorney General Louis Lefkowitz, and State Comptroller Charles Wilson.
  - 1967
    - Governor NAR 1967 Inauguration, 1967 January 2; Sound, Color, 33 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel III 14.1 Fg 10, Reel AV 1740, Box 2, Dvd AV 1379)
      Inauguration in the Assembly Chamber in Albany, NY. Benediction is given by Dr. Sandy Ray of the Cornerstone Baptist Church in Brooklyn, NY.
    - Annual Message to Legislature, 1967 January 4; Magnetic, Color, 60 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel III 14.1 Fg 12-Fg 15, Reel AV 1862)
      Unedited footage of NAR annual address in the Assembly Chambers in Albany, NY.
  - 1968
    - Rockefeller - The Presidential Man, 1968; Sound, Color, 30 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel III 14.1 Fe 26, Reel AV 1765)
      30-minute version of campaign film, with introduction by Lieutenant General James Gavin. Produced by Robert Drew Films.
    - Rockefeller - The Man Who Can, 1968; Sound, Color, 60 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel III 14.1 Fg 22, Reel AV 1815)
      One-hour version of campaign film. Produced by Robert Drew Films
    - Annual Message to Legislature, 1968 January 3; Silent, Color, 24 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1820, Reel AV 1814)
      Unedited footage of NAR annual speech to the New York State Legislature, filmed in the Assembly Room at the Capitol in Albany, NY.
    - Episode of Panorama with NAR, 1968 February; Sound, Black & white, 29 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel III 14.1 Ff 21, Reel AV 1743)
      A BBC program from 1968 February which includes some footage used in the 1964 biographical film, "The Nelson Rockefeller Story"
    - Declaration of Non-Candidacy, 1968 March 21; Sound, Color, 30 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel III 14.1 Fg 7-Fg 9, Reel AV 1085)
      In speech at the Hilton Hotel in NYC, Nelson Rockefeller declares he will not run for the 1968 presidency, in New York.
    - Declaration as Active Candidate, 1968 April 30; Silent, Color, 10 minutes. Available on DVD. (Box 2, Dvd AV 1385, Reel III 14.1 Fb 13, Reel AV 1569)
      Nelson Rockefeller reverses his previous announcement about the 1968 presidency, in Philadelphia, PA.
    - Rockefeller Statement, 1968 April 30; Sound, Color, 30 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel III 14.1 Fe 23, Reel AV 1661)
      NAR declares his candidacy, in Albany NY.
    - Gov. Rockefeller at World Affairs Council in Philadelphia, 1968 May 1; Sound, Color, 40 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel III 14.1 Fg 18, Reel AV 1089)
      NAR address on foreign policy, "The Building of a Just World Order"
    - 1968 Republican National Convention, 1968 August 7-8; Sound, Color negative, 40 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel AV 1634, Box 1, Dvd 3.15, Reel III 14.1 Fe 25, Reel III 14.1 Fe 24, Reel AV 1635)
      Footage NAR, Winthrop Rockefeller, and others from convention; nomination of NAR by Gov. Raymond Schafer (PA); thank-you speeches from NAR and wife; other footage from NBC.
    - Crime Control Week, 1968 December; Sound, Color, 2 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1112, Reel III 14.1 Fa68)
      TV spot on the State Police sent to all local TV stations for use during the week of 1968 December 2.
    - 1968 Year-End Interview, 1968 December 20; Sound, Color, 13 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel AV 1362, Box 2, Dvd AV 1362, Reel III 14.1 Ff 48)
      NAR interview by Gabe Pressman
    - Speech at Polish Home Picnic in Auburn NY, 1968; Sound, Black & white, 30 seconds. Available on DVD. (Reel III 14.1 Fa 95, Box 1, Dvd AV 3.3, Reel AV 1246)
      NAR speech during presidential campaign filmed by Mrs. Dorcas Tucker of North Carolina.
  - 1969
    - Message to Legislature, 1969 January 8; Silent, Color, 40 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel III 14.1 Fg 19, Reel AV 1943, Reel AV 1942, Reel III 14.1 Fg 20)
      NAR annual message to the NYS legislature, Albany, NY.
    - 1969 Town Meeting with Gov. Rockefeller, 1969 January 29; Sound, Color, 30 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1748, Reel III 14.1 Ff 36)
      Town meetings at Roberson Center in Binghamton, NY and Howard Johnson in Elmira, NY.
    - A New Crown for the Empire State, 1969 May; Sound, Color, 15 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel III 14.1 Fg23, Box 2, Dvd AV 1388, Reel AV 1857, Box 1, Dvd AV 3.43)
      NBC News piece about the reconstruction of the South Mall in Albany, NY. Broadcast on New York Illustrated, 1969 May.
    - Today Show Interview with NAR, 1969 May 13; Sound, Color, 10 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel III 14.1 Fb 56, Box 1, Dvd 3.16, Reel AV 1679)
      Aline Saarinen of NBC News interviews NAR about gift of primitive art collection to the Metropolitan Museum of Art, intercut with scenes of exhibition and featured pieces.